<act xml:lang="en" rubric="Census Act">
  <antecedent>
    <whereas>most countries nowadays have a census</whereas>
    <whereas>a census can provide a lot of information about the current citizens of Talossa and those of the past</whereas>
    <whereas>a census will allow the collection of specific information from all citizens of Talossa which can aid Talossa in
        future projects</whereas>
    <whereas>it will also allow comparison between Talossa of yesteryear and today</whereas>
    <whereas>there is currently no legal framework in place to hold a census in Talossa</whereas>
  </antecedent>
  <consequent>
    <therefore>be it enacted by the Ziu;
      <section num="1">
        <subsection num="1">The Seneschal may, from time to time issue an “Order of Census”, instructing that a census shall be
            taken for Talossa, or for any part(s) of Talossa, and any Order under this section must state:
          <orderedlist>
            <item>The time period on which the census will be taken;</item>
            <item>The persons by whom and with respect to whom the returns for the purpose of the census are to be made;</item>
            <item>The particulars to be stated in the returns; and</item>
            <item>The person(s) who shall be appointed Chief Enumerator.</item>
          </orderedlist>
        </subsection>
        <subsection num="2">An Order shall not be made under this section so as to require a census to be taken in any part of
            Talossa in any month, unless 6 months have elapsed since the last census was last taken in that part of
            Talossa.</subsection>
        <subsection num="3">No particulars shall be required to be stated other than the following particulars:
          <orderedlist>
            <item>Names, sex, age.</item>
            <item>Occupation, education, profession, trade or employment.</item>
            <item>Nationality, birthplace, race, language.</item>
            <item>Place of abode and character of dwelling.</item>
            <item>Talossa</item>
            <item>Condition as to marriage, relation to head of family, children.</item>
            <item>Religion</item>
          </orderedlist>
        </subsection>
        <subsection num="4">Any Order made under this section may be revoked, amended or varied by a subsequent Order.</subsection>
      </section>
      <section num="2">
        <subsection num="1">It shall be the duty of the Chief Enumerator to make such arrangements and do all such things as are
            necessary for the taking of a census in accordance with the provisions of this Act and regulations made by the Order
            of Census, and for that purpose to make arrangements for the preparation and issue of the necessary forms and
            instructions, and for the collection of the forms when filled up.</subsection>
        <subsection num="2">The Chief Enumerator, in the exercise of his powers and in the performance of his duties under this Act
            or under the Order of Census or regulations made thereunder, shall be subject to the control of, and comply with, any
            directions given by the Seneschal and/or his appointed Minister.</subsection>
        <subsection num="3">Any expenses incurred with the sanction of the Minister of Finance in connection with the taking of a
            census or otherwise in connection with the exercise of Chief Enumerator's powers or the performance of his duties under
            this Act shall be defrayed out of monies provided by the Royal Treasury.</subsection>
        <subsection num="4">The Chief Enumerator shall, as soon as may be after the taking of a census:
          <orderedlist>
            <item>Prepare reports on the census returns, and every such report shall be made available online and laid before the
                Ziu; and</item>
            <item>Send all reports on the census, to the Royal Archivist, who shall be responsible for the safe, secure and
                publically assessable archiving of this information.</item>
          </orderedlist>
        </subsection>
        <subsection num="5">The Chief Enumerator may, at his own discretion and at whim, appoint or dismiss a Deputy and/or citizens
            of Talossa to aid him in his duties and responsibilities under this Act.</subsection>
      </section>
      <section num="3">
        <subsection num="1">If the Chief Enumerator or any person who is—
          <orderedlist>
            <item>under the control of the Chief Enumerator; or</item>
            <item>a supplier of any services to him,</item>
          </orderedlist>
          discloses any personal census information to another person, without lawful authority, he shall be guilty of an offence.
        </subsection>
        <subsection num="2">If any person discloses to another person any personal census information which he knows has been
            disclosed in contravention of this Act, he shall be guilty of an offence.</subsection>
        <subsection num="3">It shall be a defence for a person charged with an offence under subsection (a) or (b) to prove—
          <orderedlist>
            <item>that at the time of the alleged offence he believed—
              <orderedlist>
                <item>that he was acting with lawful authority; or</item>
                <item>that the information in question was not personal census information; and</item>
              </orderedlist>
            </item>
            <item>that he had no reasonable cause to believe otherwise.</item>
          </orderedlist>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </therefore>
  </consequent>
  <subscribers>
    <swear>Uréu q'estadra så:</swear>
    <signature>
      <title>HM Government, represented by:</title>
      Litz Cjantscheir, Seneschal, MC, RUMP
    </signature>
  </subscribers>
</act>
