<act xml:lang="en" rubric="Unnamed Act">
  <antecedent>
    <whereas>Talossa has seven provinces, and</whereas>
    <whereas>only two of those provinces have shown any signs of activity
        during the last two periods of inactivity, and</whereas>
    <whereas>a province needs a few active citizens to keep the province alive,
        and</whereas>
    <whereas>it will take a lot of time for the kingdom to gain enough citizens
        for seven provinces to be active, and</whereas>
    <whereas>if there were less provinces, most provinces would have more
        (active) citizens), and</whereas>
    <whereas>a transition from seven to five provinces needs wide support, both
        nationally and provincially, and</whereas>
    <whereas>I don’t want to create a very detailed plan without knowing
        whether it has enough support, and</whereas>
    <whereas>if someone comes up with a proposal to create fewer provinces and
        it does not pass, it still won’t be certain whether it failed because
        there is no support for fewer provinces or because a majority has
        problems with some details of the proposal, and</whereas>
    <whereas>according to the Organic Law, article XX, section 10, “Legislation
        may be enacted by the people through the Referendum. The Cosâ may
        prepare referenda and submit these to popular vote, as it sees fit. The
        referendum may be advisory (a non-binding public opinion check) or may
        have the force of law upon its approval by a majority of those who vote
        on it. Referenda questions appear on the ballot during the next general
        election, or sooner, if the Seneschál so chooses to authorize.”,
        now</whereas>
  </antecedent>
  <consequent>
    <therefore>an advisory referendum shall be held during the General Elections
        in which all citizens shall be asked to answer the following two
        questions:
      <orderedlist>
        <item>Do you think Talossa should have five provinces instead of
            seven?</item>
        <item>Do you support a fusion between your province and another
            province?</item>
      </orderedlist>
    </therefore>
  </consequent>
  <subscribers>
    <swear>Uréu q'estadra sa;</swear>
    <signature>Flip Molinar (MC-PPT)</signature>
  </subscribers>
</act>
