<act xml:lang="en" identifier="42RZ6" rubric="Ensuring Monarch Representation
Amendment">
  <antecedent>
    <whereas>acccording to Article XVII, Section 9 <blockquote>"Each Province
        shall govern itself in such a manner as to guarantee its citizens the
        full protection of their rights under this Organic Law. Provincial
        elections may, if so specified in a Province's constitution, be
        conducted by the Chancery at the same time as elections to the Cosâ,
        and in accordance with the national election laws and rules. The King
        shall appoint a Cunstavál (or Constable) for each Province. Until such
        time as the King or Cunstavál proclaims a provincial constitution
        providing otherwise, a Province's Cunstavál shall serve as Military
        Governor and may exercise all the powers of the provincial government.
        No Cunstavál shall proclaim any provincial constitution or
        constitutional amendment which:
        Conflicts with any provision of this Organic Law,
        Grants to the King (and consequently to the Cunstavál as the King's
        representative in the Province) royal powers less extensive than those
        granted to the King on the national level, except that the provincial
        royal powers need not include a right of dissolution if provincial
        elections are held concurrently with Cosâ elections,
        Fails to provide a right to appeal decisions of the provincial court or
        courts (if any) to the Cort pü Înalt or such other national courts as
        may be created by the Ziu, or
        In the case of the adoption of a new constitution, is not approved by a
        referendum in which at least either a majority of all citizens of the
        province or a two-thirds majority of votes actually cast is in favor of
        the constitution."</blockquote>, and</whereas>
    <whereas>four of our seven provinces do not have a Cunstaval, and</whereas>
    <whereas>the king is too busy to do all the provincial stuff himself,
        and</whereas>
    <whereas>activity levels in provinces are terribly low, now</whereas>
  </antecedent>
  <consequent>
    <therefore>the following section shall be inserted in article XVII of the
        organic law, after section 9:
      <blockquote>
          "Section 10. A cunstaval will vacate his/her position when
          he/she dies, resigns, fails to vote in a election for the Cosa or is
          removed from office by the king. A cunstaval may only be removed from
          office when the king is able to appoint a replacement immediatly. Any
          province that has been without a cunstaval for more than one month may
          appoint someone to the vacant position according to a procedure
          provided for by the constitution of said province. In case no such
          procedure is provided for, the Senator of said province may appoint
          someone to the vacant position",
      </blockquote>
    </therefore>
    <furthermore>all sections in article XVII of the Organic Law, following
        the new section 10 shall be renumbered accordingly.</furthermore>
  </consequent>
  <subscribers>
    <swear>Noi urent q'estadra sa</swear>
    <signature>Tycho van Die (Senator, Cézembre)</signature>
    <signature>Flip Molinar (MC, PPT)</signature>
  </subscribers>
</act>
