<act xml:lang="en" identifier="42RZ4" rubric="The Clerk of Courts Act">
  <antecedent>
    <whereas>we have a legal system which continues to develop and grow with
        our Kingdom and</whereas>
    <whereas>there has been some criticism of the manner in which court cases
        were handled in terms of timeliness and</whereas>
    <whereas>we presently have no formal means of bringing action against a
        person or entity through our system of Courts so</whereas>
  </antecedent>
  <consequent>
    <therefore>we establish the office of Clerk of Courts. The Clerk shall be
        an apolitical position appointed by the reigning Monarch upon
        recommendation of the Prime Minister and shall serve in the following
        capacities:
      <ordered-list>
        <item>The clerk shall receive and file actions brought by individuals
            or their representative attorneys and assign to each requested
            action a docket number.</item>
        <item>The clerk shall then assign the case to a Judge, Magistrate or
            Justice in the lowest court holding jurisdiction over the
            matter.</item>
        <item>Judicial assignments shall be made in descending order of
            seniority. In cases where a clear conflict of interest should
            arise, the clerk shall assign the case to the next jurist in that
            order.</item>
        <item>The clerk shall maintain a record of docket numbers and judicial
            assignments to be archived along with the final disposition of the
            case for ease of reference.</item>
        <item>This file shall be available to any citizen for use in the
            preparation of legal strategy, the study of law or for any
            legitimate purpose.</item>
        <item>Appeals shall be filed as separate actions and will be assigned
            new docket numbers but shall be archived together with the
            original action for ease of reference.</item>
        <item>The Clerk shall acknowledge the receipt of any filing and shall,
            within 72 business hours of said acknowledgment, assign a docket
            number and make a judicial assignment.</item>
        <item>The individual holding the office of Clerk of Courts shall enjoy
            immunity from civil or criminal suit for any actions performed in
            the course of his or her official duties while holding this
            office. This immunity shall be lost upon leaving office. Due to
            the nature of the Clerk's responsibilities, an individual may not
            hold the office of Clerk of Courts, or any deputy thereunder,
            while simultaneously holding office as a Justice, Judge or
            Magistrate of the Uppermost Cort or any national inferior
            court.</item>
        <item>The Clerk of Courts serves at the pleasure of the King and may
            be dismissed by royal decree. In the case of alleged misconduct,
            the Clerk of Courts may be removed from office by Prime
            Dictate.</item>
        <item>Any individual who shall be found to have accepted bribe or
            other gratuities for the purposes of manipulating the assignment
            of jurists shall be guilty of public corruption of an officer of
            the Court, a felony, and shall suffer a punishment to be
            determined by the court.</item>
      </ordered-list>
    </therefore>
  </consequent>
  <subscribers>
    <swear>Uréu q'estadra sa;</swear>
    <signature>Capt. T.M. Asmourescu, Senator-Benito</signature>
  </subscribers>
</act>
