<act xml:lang="en" identifier="42RZ5" rubric="The Legal Representation Act">
  <antecedent>
    <whereas>we currently have the infrastructure for the designation of
        attorneys and</whereas>
    <whereas>the functions and responsibilities of attorneys have not been
        outlined elsewhere and so</whereas>
  </antecedent>
  <consequent>
    <therefore>, we establish the following guidelines for the practice of law
        within the realm:
      <ordered-list>
        <item>The practice of law shall be defined as the representation of
            individuals, corporations and government bodies before the
            Uppermost Cort, Military or Provincial Court, or any inferior
            court established by the Ziu; or the professional discussion or
            advice on matters of a legal nature.</item>
        <item>Practice before the Uppermost Cort or any inferior National
            Court established by the Ziu shall be limited to members of the
            Royal Talossan Bar who maintain their membership in good
            standing.</item>
        <item>Practice before Military Courts shall be restricted to members
            of the Royal Talossan Bar or to any commissioned officer granted
            waiver by the Minister of Defence to serve as a legal
            representative, pursuant to Ministry of Defence guidelines.</item>
        <item>Practice before Provincial Courts shall be governed by
            Provincial Law.</item>
        <item>No part of this law shall limit an individual's ability to
            represent themselves before any court of the realm.</item>
        <item>Provincial Premiers shall have the authority to represent their
            Province, in actions brought before a National Court, as a
            function of their office. This responsibility may be delegated
            only to a member of the Royal Talossan Bar. The role of the
            premier, or any Provincial official, within the provincial court
            system shall be regulated by applicable provincial law.</item>
        <item>The use of titles such as lawyer, attorney, barrister, solicitor,
            or councillor/counselor-at-law or any other title reserved by
            guidelines of the Royal Talossan Bar shall be restricted to those
            who are licensed to engage in the practice of law within the
            realm.</item>
      </ordered-list>
    </therefore>
  </consequent>
  <subscribers>
    <swear>Uréu q'estadra sa;</swear>
    <signature>T.M. Asmourescu, Senator of Benito</signature>
  </subscribers>
</act>
